<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data processing on Qiang</title>
    <link>http://yq-ericug.github.io/tags/data-processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data processing on Qiang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://yq-ericug.github.io/tags/data-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Creat Dataless SEED</title>
      <link>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/dataless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/dataless/</guid>
      <description>2020年第一篇博客。如何手动创建地震数据类型 Dataless ？ 利用 PDCC 可以创建 Dataless seed 文件，但最困难的部分可能是需要地震仪器的 RESP 格式响应文件；大多数情况下极点</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate P-wave Peak Amplitude</title>
      <link>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/p_max_amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/p_max_amp/</guid>
      <description>![](http://eqseis.geosc.psu.edu/~cammon/HTML/Classes/IntroQuakes/Notes/Images_specific02/seis_amp.gif)  Magnitude was the first quantitative measure of earthquake size based on seismograms. The maximum or &amp;ldquo;peak&amp;rdquo; ground motion is defined as the largest absolute value of ground motion recorded on a seismogram.
 Taking the 2011-03-11 Tohoku great earthquake as an example, at first, download broad-band seismic data in vertical direction from the global seismic stations (GSN) using Web Service Fetch scripts, and then convert data format from miniseed to SAC with software mseed2sac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BP Manual 07-Back-projecting in high frequency band</title>
      <link>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/bp_high/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/bp_high/</guid>
      <description>The part is main body of Back-projection.
 After preprocessing in a low frequency band, waveforms have been aligned preliminarily. Next we start to cross correlate with a higher frequency band and stack waveforms for all grid points.
set cl = 2 # upper bound of low frequency band set ch = 0.5 # lower bound of low frequency band  $ csh back-projection_2.csh
# open back-projection_2.csh to look over all commands</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BP Manual 06-Preprocessing in low frequency band</title>
      <link>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/propress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/propress/</guid>
      <description>Now, all the preparations have been done. Let&amp;rsquo;s start the key part of back-projection.
 We often cross correlate waveforms in a relatively lower frequency band, and then crosse correlate for a higher frequency bands again. This two-step procedure gives a good high-frequency station correction and avoids errors that may be caused by cycle slip in the higher frequencies.
Copy all seismic files that have been checked in the Chapter 2, make sure that there are not repeating stations and all files have an equal delta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BP Manual 03-Checking Data</title>
      <link>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/check_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yq-ericug.github.io/post/check_data/</guid>
      <description>Before starting back-projection, we need check seismic data firstly.
 Download data We recommend to download data recorded at verticle components of dense seismic stations. And convert seismic data to .SAC format.
Select stations Back-projection is a form of time-reversal where we approximate the P wave Green’s function as a time-shifted delta function. This work agrees with tele-seismic arrivals between 30° and 90° where pulses are simple and amplitude variations are small.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>